<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: noob | Assemblying Scottbot]]></title>
  <link href="http://scootcho.github.io/blog/categories/noob/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://scootcho.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-31T12:02:07+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://scootcho.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Scott Yu]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[scott.tj.yu@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to the Bay]]></title>
    <link href="http://scootcho.github.io/blog/2014/06/13/back-to-the-bay/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-13T08:15:48+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://scootcho.github.io/blog/2014/06/13/back-to-the-bay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I almost forgot how fresh and crisp the air is in San Francisco! After spending 9 months with the team in South East Asia, I can&rsquo;t say I miss the humidity one bit.</p>

<p>Since we&rsquo;re a small team, I&rsquo;m doing various things ranging from business development to cleaning the toilet (no, literally). But one of the things I enjoy the most is contributing to our web application!</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Although my background is in Finance, I&rsquo;ve always had an interest in tech and I was learning some front-end things on my own. When I got the chance to design the responsive email template, I was stoked! Although, the code is nothing worth mentioning, and the design was pieced together from different sources, it was still empowering to see the work going out to our customers in the real world.</p>

<p>I was hooked! Since then, I&rsquo;ve been taking oneline courses on my spare time. My goal is to become a better coder so I can help build cool things. Currently, I&rsquo;m learning the Ruby language, Rails framework, and Javascript. I will document my learning process here so one day I can look back and say to myself, &ldquo;hey, you&rsquo;ve come a long way!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
